barbour.com 2015-11-17

# Barbour

This is Barbour’s privacy policy. It tells you who we are, how we collect information about you, how we store and process that information, what we use it for, with whom we intend to share your information, and our practices regarding your personal data. Please read the policy carefully. If you do not agree with it, then please do not use our website or give your data to us.

#### Who we are

Our company name is J. Barbour & Sons Ltd and our trading name is Barbour. Our registered address is Simonside, South Shields, Tyne & Wear, NE34 9PD.

If you have any queries about the information we hold on you or this privacy policy, please contact our Finance and IT Director, who you may write to at the address above.

#### How we collect information

We may collect and process the following information about you in the following ways:-

**Information you give us**

You may give us information about you by filling in forms on our site www.barbour.com or by corresponding with us by phone, email or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register to use our site, subscribe to our services, search for a product, place an order on our site, use social media functions or enter a competition, promotion or survey operated by us. The information you give us may include your name, address, email address and phone number, credit card information and sometimes personal description and photograph.

**Information we collect about you**

We use cookies on Barbour.com. By using cookies, we’re able to enhance your customer experience and provide you with content and products that are relevant and available in the region in which you’re currently located. To find out more about how we use cookies, click here.

We use analytics cookies (including Google Analytics) to help us evaluate use of our site (for example popular areas) and improve the functionality of our site. We do not use this information for any other purpose.

**Information we receive from other sources**

We may receive information about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or other services we provide. We also work closely with third parties including, for example, business partners, website developers, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies and may receive information about you from them.

#### Storage of information

Your information will be stored on our secure web server and we will keep our own backup copy. We may also store your information on paper at our offices.

We will keep your information secure by taking appropriate technical and organisational measures against its unauthorised or unlawful processing and against its accidental loss, destruction or damage.

You have a statutory right to see a copy of the information we hold about you on payment of a fee, which is currently £10.

#### What we use your information for

We will use your information to provide you with any further details or information you request when you contact us.

If we provide an online shopping service we will use your information to fulfil your order.

#### With whom we may share your data

We may share your information with selected third parties including:-

business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with you;

advertisers and advertising networks that require the data to select and send relevant adverts to you;

analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site.

We will disclose your information in order to comply with any legal obligation or in order to enforce or apply our website terms and conditions or to protect the rights, property or security of others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purpose of fraud protection.

We may share your information with other companies in the same group structure as J Barbour & Sons Ltd, for example, our US subsidiary, Barbour Inc. or, our Europe subsidiary, Barbour (Europe) Ltd. We may also share your information with our distributors and authorised retailers in order to fulfil an order from you and provide customer service.

The credit or debit card details you supply will be stored by the external payment provider and your card issuer for payment processing reasons. Barbour will not store any card payment data.

From time to time we may work with external partners to undertake marketing activities. In these instances we will only share your information with these partners where at the time of data capture you have given us permission to share your information with them.

### YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes.

#### Opting-out of marketing emails

Barbour will periodically send you marketing emails only if you have given your consent using one of our online forms or, for example, if you have entered a Barbour competition (and click the relevant box) . If you no longer wish to receive marketing emails from Barbour you can unsubscribe by clicking on the relevant link in the footer of the email or alternatively you can contact the Barbour team via email at customercare@barbour.com. When marketing emails are sent to you, we may place a small graphic in the footer of your email. This graphic allows us to improve your email experience and make it more tailored to your preferences. The result is that when you open an email and view the images within it, this graphic is downloaded from our server. We will treat your opening of the email as consent to tailor your email preferences in this way.

#### Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us, one of our suppliers or one of our subsidiaries such as Barbour Inc. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

#### Changes to our Privacy Policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.
